<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Act discharging solicitations. Edinburgh, the sixth of November, 1677.</title>
            <author>Scotland. Court of Session.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B43930</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">690988668</idno>
  <idno type="VID">211687</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240872387</idno>
  
            <idno type="OCLC"> 690988668</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocn 690988668</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1371</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B43930)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 211687)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2984:16)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Act discharging solicitations. Edinburgh, the sixth of November, 1677.</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Court of Session.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the Heir of Andrw [sic] Anderson, printer to His most Sacred Majesty,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>anno Dom. 1677.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Royal arms precede title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  History --  1660-1688 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  Politics and government --  1660-1688 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:211687:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:211687:2"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>C R</head>
                  <q xml:lang="frm">HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon surmounted by a crown</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>ACT Discharging Solicitations</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>EDINBƲRGH,</hi>
                  <date>the sixth of <hi>November,</hi> 1677.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Lords of Council and Session taking to their serious consideration, that by several Acts of <hi>Sederunt,</hi> the Lords have formerly prohibited all Solicitations in Causes depending before them, whereby Parties did endeavour and expect Favour by the credit and moyen of themselves or their friends interposing with the Lords, and personal respects not relating to the Cause, to the great discouragement of others who had not the like friendship or moven, and to the great trouble of all, conceiving it their interest, and that it might be looked on as a slight or neglect if they did not upon all occasions, by themselves or their friends, solicite the whole Lords at their houses, lying scattered through the several places of the City, imagining thereby to have much promoved their Interest, and payed respect to the Lords, who have no regard to, but are troubled with such Solicitations, it being their duty and design to do Justice to all impartially, without respect of Persons. Notwithstanding of which Acts and Endeavours of the Lords against Solicitations, the same have been revived, upon pretence of giving information in the Cause; But now seing written Informations are become ordinary, and that all that ought to be represented to the Lords in any case, may easily and without trouble be done by written Informations sent to the Lords by a servant, which they will heartily accept, and will not faile to peruse; and finding it infeasible to hinder Solicitati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, so long as they admit of verbal Informations: Therefore, the Lords do declare, that they will admitt of no Solicitation, or verbal Information in any Cause depending, or that shall depend before them, during the dependance thereof, either by the Parties themselves, or any other person: And to the end the same may be effectual against all importunity, the saids Lords do enact and declare, That it shal be a relevant reason of Declinator against any of the saids Lords ordinary or extraordinary, that they have received or heard any Solicitation or verbal Information in the Cause during the dependance thereof, but upon the first observing that the matter offered to be spoken to them did bear or import any Solicitation or verbal Information in a Cause depending, if they did not use all the means they could to stop or withdraw to hear any further thereof; or in case any Solicitation or Information in a Cause depending be offered by a missive Letter, if they do not present the same to the Lords. Like as the saids Lords do strictly prohibite all Advocats, Clerks, Writers, and others depending on the Colledge of Justice, or their servants, to offer to any of the Lords any Solicitation or Information by word or letter, by only by written Infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mations, Bills, or Tickets for calling, under the pain of deprivation, and being secluded from the house, excepting the Clerk of the Process, for clearing any Interloquitor or Minute in the Cause. Likeas, the saids Lords do declare, That if any Party or others of the Leidges, offer any Solicitation or Information, by Word or Missive, that they will amerciat them as followes, <hi>viz.</hi> Every Nobleman, in three hundred Merks scots; every Baron or Knight, in two hundred Merks; every other Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor, Gentleman, or chief Burgess, in one hundred pounds; and every other person in one hundred Merks <hi>toties quoties,</hi> to be applyed for the use of the poor. It is alwayes hereby declared, That the verbal Information of any party, or other person for him when required or allowed judicially, or before Auditors, in Dyets appointed for both parties to be heard, or before the Ordinaties upon the Bills, in relation to the passing of Bills of Suspension or Advocation, or before any of the Lords to whom either by consent of Parties, or by appointment or Recommendation of the Lords, an Accommodation in any Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cess is referred, is no wayes hereby prohibited: And to the effect the Leidges may be secured against any prejudice which they may apprehend by debarring them from Solicitation or verbal Information, the Lords do declare, That there shall be free access for all persons to inform them by written Informations only, to be delivered by servants, and that in all cases from time to time. And for the more sure delivery of Informations, they ordaine, that every one of the Lords shall have a servant attending in his house from five a clock to eight a clock at night, who shall be holden to receive any Informations, doubles of Bills, or Tickets for calling, that shall be given in, without payment of any money, under such pain or punishment as the Lords shall think fit: And which Informations, Bills, and Tickets shall be delivered by the servants of Advocats, or of the Parties, or other servants, and by none others. And ordains this Act to be affixed on the wall of the utter House, and to be printed, that none pretend ignorance thereof. Extracted out of the Books of <hi>Sederunt</hi> by,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Al Gibson.</signed>
               <lb/> GOD save the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the <hi>Heir</hi> of <hi>Andrw Anderson,</hi> Printer to His most Sacred Majesty. <hi>Anno Dom.</hi> 1677.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>